Phyllis McGinley Papers
Phyllis McGinley Papers
1897-1978
McGinley, Phyllis, 1905-1978
36.0 linear ft.
The Phyllis McGinley Papers comprise personal and business correspondence, writings, and memorabilia. Spanning 1897 to 1978, the collection reflects not only the professional career of the American humorist and Pulitzer Prize-winning poet, but also the wide scope of her audience. Writings include, for any given title, any combination of work sheets, manuscripts, production records, and published versions for McGinley's books, essays, interviews, lyrics, poetry, reviews, scripts, speeches and stories. Memorabilia consists primarily of financial, legal, and printed materials, photographs and scrapbooks.
144588
Biographical History
American poet, essayists, humorist, lyricist, teacher.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Phyllis McGinley Papers comprise personal and business correspondence, writings, and memorabilia. Spanning 1897 to 1978, the collection reflects not only the professional career of the American humorist and Pulitzer Prize-winning poet, but also the wide scope of her audience.
The Correspondence-subject files (Boxes 1-29) contain biographical material, family correspondence, and general personal and business letters. The correspondence is almost exclusively incoming, however there are a few photocopies of McGinley's outgoing letters scattered throughout various files. The collection contains letters from a number of literary figures (Richard Armour, Cass Canfield, Peter De Vries, Richard Eberhart, John Holmes, Jean and Walter Kerr, Marianne Moore, Lewis Mumford, Anne Sexton, A.M. Sullivan, Louis Untermeyer, John Updike, E.B. and Katharine White, Thornton Wilder); clergymen (Daniel Berrigan, Richard Cushing, John Haynes Holmes, Sister Mary Madeleva, Joseph Ritter, Francis Spellman, Francis Sweeney); composers and lyricists (Elizabeth Gould, Oscar Hammerstein, Gladys Rich, Richard Rodgers, Orvis Ross); entertainers (Katharine Cornell, Hume Cronyn, Irene Dunne, Tom Ewell, Helen Hayes, Peter Lind Hayes, Mary Healy, Groucho Marx, Walter Slezak, Jane Wyatt); and politicians (Stanley M. Isaacs, Jacob Javits, Eugene McCarthy, Nelson Rockefeller, Sargent Shriver, Stewart Udall, Robert F. Wagner). There are few long runs of personal correspondence of significant depth or duration.
The importance of the correspondence lies in its illumination of both McGinley's business relationship with agent Curtis Brown Inc. and the extraordinary range of publications to which she was a frequent contributor (America, The American Scholar, The Commonweal, The Critic, Good Housekeeping, Harper's Magazine, Ladies' Home Journal, Mademoiselle, The New Yorker, The Reader's Digest, The Saturday Evening Post, The Saturday Review, The Sign, Woman's Day). A teacher and author of children's books as well as a poet, essayist, and lyricist, McGinley, in a career which spanned more than four decades, maintained business relationships with a variety of publishers over a number of years (Collier Books, Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Inc., J.B. Lippincott, Macmillan, G. Schirmer, Viking Press, Franklin Watts, Inc.). A significant portion of the correspondence centers around the various honors and awards which were bestowed on McGinley. A recipient of the Pulitzer Prize for poetry in 1961, she received a number of honorary Doctor of Letters degrees (Boston College, Dartmouth College, Marquette University, St. John's University, Smith College, Wheaton College, Wilson College) as well as the Catholic Book Club's Campion Award (1967), the Catholic Institute of the Press Award (1960), and the Laetare Medal, conferred by the University of Notre Dame in 1964. She also appeared on the cover of Time the week of June 18, 1965. In 1968, selected by New York Governor Nelson Rockefeller to serve on a committee to review the State's abortion law, McGinley, a Catholic, agreed to participate in the controversial hearings and to file a report. The collection includes correspondence, a transcript of the hearings, the report, and newspaper clippings pertaining to the committee. Widely acclaimed for her wit and common-sense approach to the rigors and joys of family life in America, McGinley received an extensive assortment of fan mail (2 linear feet) from children, educators, fellow poets, librarians, and the hundreds of housewives whose lives she championed from the earliest beginnings of the women's movement in the 1960s through the mid-1970s.
Writings (Boxes 30-49) include, for a given title, any combination of work sheets, manuscripts, production records, and published versions for McGinley's books, essays, interviews, lyrics, poetry, reviews, scripts, speeches, and stories. The many manuscript drafts of McGinley's writings reveal her method of composition for various works. Perhaps most interesting are her essays, for which she often composed a "serious" version before producing her characteristically humorous final manuscript. Suburbia and sainthood are the prominent topics of McGinley's writing, together with occasional pieces produced for various holidays, especially Christmas. In addition to her poetry appearances in a wide variety of popular magazines, McGinley also produced a number of verses which were used commercially, including advertisements for Book Week, Calvert Distillers Corporation, Coty, The New Yorker, and Seagram-Distillers Corporation. Among the miscellaneous writings are a journal (1949-1951), an assortment of juvenilia, and the manuscript draft of "The Emperor's Nightingale," a narrative adaptation of the Hans Christian Andersen classic.
Memorabilia consists primarily of financial, legal, and printed materials, photographs, and scrapbooks. Included among the financial material are royalty statements (arranged by publisher) for McGinley's books and bank check records. Legal material includes a chronological arrangement of contracts (1928-1974) and an assortment of copyright renewals and transfers. Printed material consists of articles about McGinley as well as publicity for and reviews of her many books. A series of scrapbooks contain a variety of items, but also include printed material by and about McGinley.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Writings are subdivided by style (books, essays, etc.) and within that are arranged alphabetically by title. Memorabilia is arranged alphabetically by type of item, with separate subsections for financial and legal material.
Subject and Genre Headings
Women Authors; Literature -- Children's; Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; McGinley, Phyllis, 1905-1978.; Abortion -- Law and legislation -- New York (State); American literature -- Irish American authors.; American poetry -- 20th century.; American poetry -- Women authors.; Children's literature.; Humorists, American.; Humorous poetry -- United States.; Irish American women.; Irish Americans.; Lyricists -- United States.; Poets, American.; Women authors, American.; Women poets, American.; United States -- Social life and customs -- 20th century.; Account books.; Calendars (documents); Check stubs.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Drafts (documents); Essays.; Galley proofs.; Interviews.; Notebooks.; Juvenilia.; Librettos (documents for music); Manuscripts for publication.; Memorabilia.; Musical scores.; Photographs.; Poems.; Reviews (documents); Scrapbooks.; Scripts (documents); Speeches (documents); Workbooks.; Educators.; Humorists.; Lyricists.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Biographical material, 1 folder (Box 1)
- Family correspondence
  - Barker, Phyllis Kiesel, 1941-1975; undated (Box 1)
  - Blake, Patsy Hayden and Richard, See Hayden, Patsy
  - Hayden, Julie, 1963-1977; undated (Box 1)
  - Hayden, Patsy, 1963-1967; undated; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Hayden family (unspecified), 1946-1968; undated (Box 1)
  - Hayden-McGinley family (general), 1924-1976; undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Kane, Allan J. and Stella, 1937-1977; undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - McGinley, Daniel and Julia (parents), 1897; 1916 (Box 2)
  - McGinley, Margaret F. (sister), 1964-1969; undated (Box 2)
  - McGinley, Marge, 1944-1976; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Moore, Ira and Etta, 1937-1973; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
- Correspondence-subject files
  - A, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Abbott, Charles David, 1945-1956 (Box 3)
  - Academy of American Poets, 1958-1969 (Box 3)
  - Adams, Franklin Pierce, 1932-1942; undated (Box 3)
  - Adams, J. Donald, 1953-1956 (Box 3)
  - Adams, James Truslow, 1934 (Box 3)
  - Adams, John Q. and Bonnie, 1956-1977; undated (Box 3)
  - Alda, Alan, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Alexander Doll Company, Inc., 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - America, 1954-1968; undated (Box 3)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1955-1967 (Box 3)
  - The American Home, 1958; 1961 (Box 3)
  - The American Scholar, 1953-1968; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Ames, Winthrop, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Amuedo, Evelyn, See Wade, Evelyn Amuedo
  - Anderson, Charles B., 1958-1969; undated (Box 3)
  - Anderson, Curtiss, 1962-1965 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, George W., 1964 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, Robert Woodruff, 1940-1955 (Box 3)
  - Annenberg, Walter, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Anton, Rita, 1965-1 66 (Box 3)
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1955-1968 (Box 3)
  - Archer, Kate Rennie, undated (Box 3)
  - Armour, Richard, 1947-1975; undated (Box 3)
  - Art Directors Club of Philadelphia, 1965; certificate of excellence (Oversize 1)
  - Ashley, Nova Trimble, 1966; 1967 (Box 3)
  - Atchley, Dana W. and Mary, 1948-1969; undated (Box 3)
  - Atheneum Publishers, 1960-1969 (Box 3)
  - Atkinson, Brooks, 1962; 1965 (Box 3)
  - The Atlantic Monthly, 1943-1965 (Box 3)
  - Auchincloss, Louis, 1952; 1966 (Box 3)
  - Auden, Wystan Hugh, 1959-1961; undated (Box 3)
  - Authors Guild, 1948-1970; undated (Box 3)
  - B, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Backus, Joseph M., 1958 (Box 4)
  - Bacon, Leonard, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
  - Baker, Samm Sinclair, 1955; 1965 (Box 4)
  - Baldwin, Faith, 1949; undated (Box 4)
  - Ballantine, Lesley Frost, 1960-1966; undated (Box 4)
  - Barber, Lylah, 1960; 1961 (Box 4)
  - Barnard College, 1952-1962; undated (Box 4)
  - Barr, Isabel Harriss, 1952; 1967,; undated (Box 4)
  - Barrows, Marjorie, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Barton, Bruce, 1955; undated (Box 4)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1951-1974; undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Basso, Hamilton, 1955; 1961 (Box 4)
  - Batchelor, C.D. (Clarence Daniel), 1933 (Box 4)
  - Beach, Peter, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Benatzky, Ralph, undated (Box 4)
  - Benet, William Rose, 1935; 1944 (Box 4)
  - Berrigan, Daniel, 1961-1967; undated (Box 4)
  - Berrigan, Philip, undated (Box 4)
  - Best, Marshall, See Viking Press Inc.
  - Bevington, Helen, 1950-1972 (Box 4)
  - Bingham, Barry and Mary, 1951-1961 (Box 4)
  - Birmingham, Stephen, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Bishop, Morris, 1941-1973; undated (Box 4)
    See also Florida Sanitarium and Hospital
  - Blettner, Margaret, 1951-1963; undated (Box 5)
  - Boatner, Maxine Tull, 1940-1953 (Box 5)
  - Boissevain, Eugen, 1939 (Box 5)
  - Book-of-the-Month Club, Inc., 1953-1969; undated (Box 5)
  - Book-of-the-Month Club, Inc. Writing Fellowship Program, 1967-1968 (Box 5)
  - Borestone Mountain Poetry Awards, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Borland, Hal, 1934 (Box 5)
  - Boslooper, Thomas David, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Boston College, 1962-1969 (Box 5)
  - Bowes, Edward (Major), 1939 (Box 5)
  - Bradford, Faith, 1959-1965 (Box 5)
  - Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Braley, Berton, 1936; undated (Box 5)
  - Braybrooke, Neville, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Bregy, Katherine, 1957-1964; undated (Box 5)
  - Brown, John Mason, 1961-1965 (Box 5)
  - [Curtis] Brown, Ltd., 1939-1977; undated; 7 folders (Box 5)
  - Browning, Colleen, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Brunini, John Gilland, 1951-1964; undated (Box 6)
  - Bullock, Marie, 1961-1977; undated (Box 6)
    See also Academy of American Poets
  - Burnett, Whit, 1969; undated (Box 6)
  - Burnshaw, Stanley, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Bush, Grace, undated (Box 6)
  - Butterfield, Frances, 1947-1960; undated (Box 6)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1954 (Box 6)
  - C, 7 folders (Box 6)
  - Callahan, Sidney, undated (Box 6)
  - Camp Fire Girls, Inc., 1941-1968; undated (Box 6)
  - Canfield, Cass, 1959-1962 (Box 6)
  - Carmer, Carl, 1946-1964; undated (Box 6)
  - Carpenter, Margaret, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Catholic Book Club, See America
  - Catholic Digest, 1954; 1955,; undated (Box 6)
  - Catholic Institute of the Press, 1961-1968; undated (Box 6)
  - Catholic Institute of the Press Award, 1960 (Oversize 2)
  - The Catholic News, 1954-1966 (Box 6)
  - Catholic Poetry Society of America, See Brunini, John Gilland
  - The Catholic Worker, 1960-1971; undated (Box 6)
  - The Catholic World, 1925-1928; 1957 (Box 6)
  - Catholic Writers Guild of America, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Chaffin, Lillie D., 1964 (Box 6)
  - Charlot, John, 1959-1969; undated (Box 6)
  - Charlot, Martin, 1967-1969 (Box 6)
  - Chicago Tribune, 1945-1967; undated (Box 7)
  - Churchill, Judith Chase, 1944-1956 (Box 7)
  - Chute, Marchette, 1961 (Box 7)
    See also National Institute of Arts and Letters
  - Ciardi, John, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Claiborne, Craig, 1964-1974; undated (Box 7)
  - Clapp, Dudley, 1954-1965; undated (Box 7)
  - Clarke, Richard, 1951-1961; undated (Box 7)
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1949-1968 (Box 7)
  - Coakley, Mary Lewis, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Coatsworth, Elizabeth Jane, 1953; 1968 (Box 7)
  - Coblentz, Stanton A., 1950 (Box 7)
  - Coffey, Thomas P., 1959 (Box 7)
  - Cohen, John Michael, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Coleman, Thomas, 1961; undated (Box 7)
  - Collier Books, 1961-1963 (Box 7)
  - Collinge, Patricia, 1945-1969; undated (Box 7)
  - Collins, Kitty, 1959-1970; undated (Box 7)
  - Colt, Amy, 1955-1978; undated (Box 7)
  - Colum, Padraic, 1954; 1968,; undated (Box 7)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc., 1952-1965 (Box 7)
  - Columbia University, 1934-1959 (Box 7)
  - Commonweal, 1927-1928; 1950-1969 (Box 7)
  - Connolly, Francis Xavier, 1973; 1974,; undated (Box 7)
  - Cooke, Alistair, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Cornell, Katharine, 1959-1963; undated (Box 7)
  - Cosgrove, Mary Silva, 1954-1962 (Box 7)
  - Cosmopolitan Club, 1953-1961; undated (Box 7)
  - Cousins, Margaret, See Good Housekeeping
  - The Cowl, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Coxhead, Elizabeth, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Crawford, Cheryl, 1943 (Box 7)
  - Crean, Robert J., 1960-1961; undated (Box 7)
  - The Critic, 1957-1974 (Box 7)
  - Cronyn, Hume, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Crosswhite, E. B., 1939 (Box 7)
  - Cummins, Virginia Kent, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Cuneo, Paul K., 1955-1969 (Box 7)
  - Cushing, Richard, 1962 (Box 7)
  - D, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Danforth, William H., 1954 (Box 7)
  - D'Arcy, Martin Cyril, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Dartmouth College, 1961; 1969; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - D'Auria, Gemma, 1957 (Box 8)
  - Davis, Lavinia R., 1952-1962; undated (Box 8)
  - Day, Dorothy, See The Catholic Worker
  - De Banke, Cecile, 1946; undated (Box 8)
  - Dell, Floyd, 1952; undated (Box 8)
  - Dell Publishing Co., 1943-1965 (Box 8)
  - [J. M.] Dent & Sons, 1955-1965 (Box 8)
  - De Vries, Peter, 1962-1970; undated (Box 8)
  - Dial Press, 1954; 1963 (Box 8)
  - Dobias, Dorathea F., 1944; undated (Box 8)
  - Dodd, Loring Holmes, 1936-1946 (Box 8)
  - Dorsey, Helen, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Doubleday, Neal Frank, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Doubleday & Company, 1934-1969 (Box 8)
  - Douglas, Kirk, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Douglas, Lloyd C., 1937 (Box 8)
  - Duell, Sloan & Pearce, 1940-1961 (Box 8)
  - Duncan, Hazel, 1954-1955; undated (Box 8)
  - Dunne, Irene, 1966; undated (Box 8)
  - Duryee, Mary Ballard, undated (Box 8)
  - [E. P.] Dutton, 1952-1965 (Box 8)
  - E, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Eaton, Anne Thaxter, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Eberhart, Richard, 1960-1968 (Box 8)
    See also Pulitzer Prize
  - Eiseley, Loren C., 1965 (Box 8)
  - Ewell, Tom, 1961; undated (Box 8)
  - F, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Family Circle, 1961; 1964,; undated (Box 8)
  - Famous Writers School, 1967-1974; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Famous Writers School - printed material, 1968-1975; undated (Box 9)
  - Fandel, John, 1959-1962 (Box 9)
  - Farrar, Margaret, 1953-1977; undated (Box 9)
  - Farrar, Straus & Giroux, Inc., 1933-1969 (Box 9)
  - Florida Sanitarium and Hospital, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - France, Simone, 1955 (Box 9)
  - Franco, Ann Redington, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Frank, Marcel G., 1964 (Box 9)
  - Franklin, Margaret Ladd, undated (Box 9)
  - Frazier, Neta Lohnes, 1956; 1959 (Box 9)
  - Freedgood, Lillian, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Freedoms Foundation, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Fremantle, Anne Jackson, 1952-1965 (Box 9)
  - French, Allen, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Friedman, Philip Allan, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Froehlich, John F., 1944; 1959 (Box 9)
  - Frost, Robert, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Frye, Burton James Conrad, 1955 (Box 9)
  - G, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Galantiere, Lewis, undated (Box 9)
  - Galbraith, Georgie Starbuck, 195 (Box 9)
  - Gallery of Living Catholic Authors, 1951; 1955,; undated (Box 9)
  - Gallup, George, 1955 (Box 9)
  - Galvin, John T. and Ruth, 1968-1973 (Box 9)
  - Gardiner, Dorothy, 1960; 1963 (Box 9)
  - Gardiner, Harold C., See America
  - Gardner, Paul, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Gibson, John E., 1944 (Box 9)
  - Gibson, W. Walker, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Ginn and Company, 1951-1965 (Box 9)
  - Glamour, 1955-1965 (Box 10)
  - Godden, Rumer, 1958-1974; undated (Box 10)
  - Goldsmith, Sophie L., 1949 (Box 10)
  - Good Housekeepinq, 1944-1973; undated (Box 10)
  - Gordi, Tooni, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Gossett, William T., 1961 (Box 10)
  - Gould, Beatrice and Bruce, 1959; 1961,; undated (Box 10)
  - Gould, Danny, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Gould, Elizabeth, 1968-1969 (Box 10)
    See also "Personal and Private Song Cycles" / Elizabeth Gould and Phyllis McGinley
  - Grafflin, Arthur C., 1965 (Box 10)
  - Gray, Mary Z., 1959; undated (Box 10)
  - Greb, Gordon B., 1973 (Box 10)
  - Greeff, Adele, 1953; 1960 (Box 10)
  - Green, Joseph C., 1953 (Box 10)
  - Greene, Constance, 1967; undated (Box 10)
  - Greene, Vivian, undated (Box 10)
  - Gross, Gerald, 1956-1969; undated (Box 10)
  - Gross, Seymour L., undated (Box 10)
  - Grosset & Dunlap, 1959 (Box 10)
  - [John Simon] Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1961-1968 (Box 10)
  - Guiterman, Arthur, 1932 (Box 10)
  - Guthrie, Tyrone, 1961 (Box 10)
  - H, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Hackett, Walter, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Hall, Elizabeth B., 1960; 1962 (Box 10)
  - Hallmark Cards, 1960-1976 (Box 10)
  - Hammerstein, Oscar, 1951 (Box 10)
  - Harbison, E. Harris, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Harcourt, Brace & World, 1937-1968 (Box 10)
  - Harlow, Arthur H. and May, 1951-1968; undated (Box 10)
  - Harper & Row, 1950-1969 (Box 10)
  - Harper's Bazaar, 1950-1954; undated (Box 10)
  - Harper's Magazine, 1950-1965 (Box 10)
  - Hay, Alden and Clarice, 1957-1977; undated (Box 10)
  - Hay, Sara Henderson, 1955 (Box 10)
  - Haydn, Hiram, 1954-1968 (Box 10)
    See also The American Scholar
  - Hayes, Helen, 1955; 1957 (Box 11)
  - Hayes, Peter Lind and Mary Healy, 1958-1968; undated (Box 11)
  - Heckscher, August, 1962 (Box 11)
  - Hedges, Doris, undated (Box 11)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Hemingway, Mary, 1965; undated (Box 11)
  - Herald Tribune Fresh Air Fund, 1953; 1955 (Box 11)
  - Herzberg, Max John, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Hewitt, Arthur W., 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Hicks, Granville, 1962 (Box 11)
  - Hill, Elizabeth Starr, 1967 (Box 11)
  - Hill, Pope R., 1951 (Box 11)
  - Hill & Wang, 1960-1974 (Box 11)
  - Hillyer, Robert S., 1952; 1953,; undated (Box 11)
  - Hoagland, Clayton, 1952 (Box 11)
  - Hochman, Sandra, 1966 (Box 11)
  - Hodnett, Edward, 1966 (Box 11)
  - Hofstead, John Andrew, 1949 (Box 11)
  - Holden, Arthur Cort, 1961; 1965 (Box 11)
  - Holden, Raymond P., 1965 (Box 11)
  - Holland, Henrietta Fort, 1954-1962; undated (Box 11)
  - Holmes, John, 1945-1962 (Box 11)
  - Holmes, John Haynes, 1961 (Box 11)
  - Henry Holt and Company, Inc., 1950 (Box 11)
  - Holt, Rinehart & Winston, Inc., See Farrar, Straus & Giroux, Inc.
  - Holzhauer, Jean, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1951 (Box 11)
  - Horgan, Paul, 1962 (Box 11)
  - Horizon Press, 1958-1968 (Box 11)
  - Horizons, undated (Box 11)
  - Horn, Gunnar, 1954; 1960,; undated (Box 11)
  - Houghton Mifflin, 1954-1966 (Box 11)
  - House & Garden, 1956-1959 (Box 11)
  - Howells, J. Harvey, 1959; 1960 (Box 11)
  - Huebsch, Ben, 1960-1961; undated (Box 11)
  - Humphries, Rolfe, 1952-1957 (Box 11)
  - Hunt, Lyman C., 1977 (Box 11)
  - Hutchens, John K., 1958; 1964,; undated (Box 11)
  - I, 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Inaugural Committee (1961) (Box 11)
  - Ingenue, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
  - Isaacs, Stanley M., 1940-1959 (Box 11)
  - J, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Jackson, Charles and Rhoda, 1945-1961; undated (Box 11)
  - Jackson, Joseph Henry, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Jackson, Shirley, undated (Box 11)
  - Jacobs, Flora Gill, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Jacobson, Emilie, 1964; 1966 (Box 11)
    See also [Curtis] Brown, Ltd.
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1961 (Box 11)
  - Jeans, Marylu Terral, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Jennison, C. S., 1959 (Box 11)
  - Johnson, Claudia Alta Taylor, 1966; 1973 (Box 11)
  - Johnson, Edith Warner, 1942 (Box 11)
  - Johnson, Paul Barton, 1974 (Box 11)
  - Joseph, John, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Justema, William, 1954 (Box 11)
  - K, 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Kadison, Alexander, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Kallen, Horace Meyer, 1942 (Box 11)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma, 1936-1970; undated; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Keefe, Nancy Quirk, 1961-1975; undated (Box 12)
  - Kehl, D. G., 1968-1977 (Box 12)
  - Kenny, Herbert A., 1962-1963; undated (Box 12)
  - Kerlan, Irvin, 1948-1951 (Box 12)
  - Kerr, Jean and Walter, 1956-1971; undated (Box 12)
  - Kerr, Walter, See Kerr, Jean and Walter
  - Keyes, Frances Parkinson, 1960-1961 (Box 12)
  - Kielty, Bernardine, See Scherman, Bernardine Kielty
  - Kieran, John, 1958 (Box 12)
  - Kimball, Fiske, 1953 (Box 12)
  - King, Marian, 1954-1961 (Box 12)
  - King Features Syndicate, 1964-1965; undated (Box 12)
  - Kirk, Grayson, 1961 (Box 12)
  - [Alfred A.] Knopf, Inc., 1959-1965; undated (Box 12)
  - Kogan, Herman, undated (Box 12)
  - Kollmar, Richard, 1942-1943 (Box 12)
  - Kronenberger, Louis, 1955; 1963,; undated (Box 12)
  - Kunstler, William M., 1959; 1960 (Box 12)
  - L, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Ladies' Home Journal, 1925-1966; undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Ladies of Charity, 1954-1961 (Box 12)
  - Landers, Ann, 1965 (Box 12)
  - Langland, Joseph, 1961; undated (Box 12)
  - Larchmont Public Library, 1951-1976; undated (Box 12)
  - Lasswell, Fred, 1943; undated (Box 12)
  - Lattimore, Richmond Alexander, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Laube, Clifford James, 1955; 1961 (Box 12)
  - Lavery, Emmet, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard, 1955; 1956 (Box 12)
  - Lechlitner, Ruth, 1940; 1941 (Box 12)
  - Leech, Margaret, 1943 (Box 12)
  - Leigh, W. Colston, 1937-1962 (Box 12)
  - Leinsdorf, Erich and Anne, 1961 (Box 12)
  - Lennon, Florence Becker, 1960-1961 (Box 12)
  - Lewin, Ralph A., 1959; 1961 (Box 12)
  - Lewis, B. Roland, 1954; undated (Box 12)
  - Lewis, Sinclair, 1937; undated (Box 12)
  - Library of Congress, 1960-1966 (Box 13)
  - Life, 1956-1969; undated (Box 13)
  - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1962 (Box 13)
  - [J. B.] Lippincott Co., 1944-1973; undated; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Little, Brown and Co., 1960-1962 (Box 13)
  - Lockwood Memorial Library, 1940; 1954 (Box 13)
    See also Abbott, Charles David
  - Lodge, Lily, 1961 (Box 13)
  - Loeser, Katinka, 1969-1976; undated (Box 13)
  - Longmans, Green & Co., Inc., 1958; 1960 (Box 13)
  - Looking Glass Library, 1959-1961; undated (Box 13)
  - Loomis, Charles Battell, 1940; 1957 (Box 13)
  - Lowenfels, Walter, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Lucas, Dione, 1957 (Box 13)
  - Luccock, Halford Edward, 1940; 1959 (Box 13)
  - Lundbergh, Holger, 1944 (Box 13)
  - Lynes, Russell, 1965; 1973,; undated (Box 13)